Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mr. Ryu, standby okay!
Good!
Amuro, standby for docking.
Ready?
I'm going in, Mr. Ryu!
5... 4...
3... 2... 1...
Laser searcher synchronized.
5... 4...
Gundam B Parts released!
Core Change! Docking, go!
Days spent training with comrades...
...to perfect the mid-air docking.
After deserting the White Base,
will the wayward Amuro...
...ever experience those days again?
For an Amuro wandering the battlefield...
...feelings similar to regret
were beginning to emerge.
Ramba Ral's Attack
A camp.
May I have some water to drink?
Don't have any to spare.
There's a town close by. Buy some there.
Is that so?
Sorry to bother you.
Can I get a meal here?
Ryu.
Do you agree with everyone else?
About Amuro?
Yeah.
Are we considering Amuro
separately from the Gundam?
Hmm... We'll make a decision about Amuro
after we get the Gundam back.
Let's forget it then.
It'll all depend on
how Amuro feels at that point.
I hate this!
- Time to get some food!
- I'm hungry!
Hey, mister. We're taking a break.
There're 13 of us.
Yes... Welcome.
Ms. Hamon, this way please.
Sorry, Sagred and Mile. You'll keep watch.
I'll make sure you're relieved soon.
Yes, Lieutenant Ramba Ral.
Ramba Ral?
Let's have some water, mister.
Sorry, Hamon...
...you must be amazed
that there's a desert this big on Earth.
It's a marvel of nature.
Much more interesting than star-gazing.
Everyone, at ease! Take a seat!
Have anything you want.
It's the last meal before our mission.
Yes, sir!
Before the mission...?
Ah, Sodon is considered neutral territory,
so no combat...
We'll do it elsewhere. Don't worry.
You don't have much here...
We'll have 14 of whatever you can do.
Yes, ma'am.
That's one too many, Hamon.
One for the boy too.
You're interested in a boy like him?
Yes, perhaps.
That's right!
At the very least, he's gotta eat!
What's that? In a place like this?
Um, I don't know how to say this...
I appreciate your generosity...
...but I can't accept.
Why?
There's no reason for you
to give me anything.
The kid's got you there, Hamon!
I just took a liking to you, that's all.
Isn't that a good enough reason?
But I...
Hey, kid. It's quite something
to be liked by Hamon.
That's right.
It's bad karma to refuse.
I wish I were in your shoes, kid.
Be thankful you were born a man!
But I'm not a beggar either.
I like you, kid.
You don't mince words.
It's not just from Hamon, it's from me too.
You can accept the meal then, right?
Huh? I didn't mean...
Lieutenant!
We found a suspicious person!
A spy?
Yes! A woman behaving strangely!
She's just a kid.
Fraw Bow!
She's a friend of yours?
Yes.
But she's wearing a Federation uniform.
You sure? It looks a little different.
I'm certain of it.
What do you think, Hamon?
Well, it looks like it.
It seems she's this boy's girlfriend.
Really.
Amuro!
Let her go!
But...
Just do it.
I like the look in your eyes.
Well, you've got some guts.
Now, I'm really impressed.
Amuro, is it?
Yes.
But if we should meet in battle,
it will be different.
Good luck, young Amuro.
Thank you, Mr. Ramba Ral.
And Ms. Hamon.
Amuro!
Let's go.
Hey!
Yes, sir!
Go follow them, Zeygan.
The only Federation forces around here
should be the Trojan Horse.
Yes, sir.
What's wrong?
I told you to leave me alone.
If you think everyone will continue
to worry about you... you're wrong.
You're the one who got caught by Zeon.
Well, what were you doing?
Amuro!
Get in.
You didn't want to hold hands with me
because that lady was watching, right?
You're wrong.
Liar.
You're just getting further and further
away from me, Amuro.
See ya.
Aren't you going to the White Base?
No.
Better get back soon,
or you'll get sunstroke.
I'm sure you'll regret this later.
I can manage on my own.
You're so stubborn!
I won't regret this!
The Trojan Horse!
Any news?
A coded message from Zeygan.
"The wind will blow soon."
Seems he found the Trojan Horse.
All right! Begin preparations for the attack!
You saw a Gouf? The enemy mobile suit?
Yes. Stowed on two large trailers.
Did you see Amuro?
Yes, I saw him in Sodon as well.
I bet Amuro told the Zeon folks
about the White Base.
Kai, enough with that!
Enemy forces are stalking us right now.
Bright...
We should stop maintenance and put the White Base on interception status.
I agree.
Fraw Bow, I understand how you feel.
But you can't just go off without permission.
I understand.
It's working well.
Stetch! How's your mobile suit?
Sir! It's running well!
Be careful, my dear.
Right. You guys advance 5 kilometers
and wait there.
Don't use the radio for now.
Right.
Are those people...
...the enemy we're fighting?
I just took a liking to you, that's all.
Is that a problem?
It's quite something
to be liked by Hamon.
So, they found the White Base!
They must have followed Fraw Bow!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
If that Gouf mobile suit shows up...
the Guncannon and Guntank are finished!
Oh no... It's so close!
Kai!
You're not getting away with it!
Mr. Ryu, get us away from White Base!
Huh?! Incoming!
Emergency takeoff!
Yes, sir!
A tank!
Hayato!
The enemy has two mobile suits!
Don't let them get any closer to White Base!
Right!
Stetch! I'll leap out...
and then you destroy the tank!
Yes, Lieutenant Ral!
Now!
Mr. Ryu! A caterpillar track was hit!
Wh-Why you...!
I did it, Lieutenant! I got the tank!
Now I'll finish him!
Haven't you been paying attention? Stetch!
We have to take out the Trojan Horse,
or there's no point to our battle!
You're right, sir...!
Damn Zaku!
Mr. Ryu! I'm doing a forced ejection
of the Guntank's upper unit! All right?!
Forced ejection?!
Hayato! What about you?!
You can't move!
Mr. Ryu, I've got plenty of ammo left!
I'll just act as a turret!
We can't waste strength!
Mr. Ryu, please take the Core Fighter
and find Amuro!
All right! I understand.
You could be right!
I'm heading out!
Launching core block!
Be careful, Hayato!
Kai, cover Hayato and the White Base!
He's got to be kidding.
Where the hell are the Gouf and Zaku?
Hayato! You should get out of there
before you're killed!
What are you saying?!
I can't move, but I still have ammo!
I'm staying!
Wow. How very noble of you!
Is the enemy up there?
Is that it?
If I use the beam rifle now,
when I fight the Gouf, I won't...
Amuro, do you read?! I'll keep it occupied!
You head over to the White Base!
Mr. Ryu! Thanks!
Mr. Ryu came to look for me.
Ascend. We're escaping.
Right on! Even the Trojan Horse can't take
a direct missile from behind!
One Zaku approaching the stern!
What?!
What about our rear missiles?
There's no one there!
It's right behind us?
Yes!
Full speed ahead! Hang on tight, everyone!
Damn that Trojan Horse!
Careless fool!
Why, you...!
Hayato! Kai! Do you read?
Can't you hit the Gouf from outside?
If you don't destroy it, the White Base will...
Bright! I'll shake off the Gouf!
What? Mirai, can you do that?
We'll have to fly upside-down.
Please fasten your seatbelts.
What about you?
Never mind!
Ms. Mirai is amazing...!
N-No...!
It's the one they call the Gundam!
Where was it hiding?
That Amuro! Finally!
Damn Gouf!
Why you...!
That's some precise firing!
As such, it's easy for the computer to predict.
He's not even dodging them!
Well, I've only got one shot left anyways...
This pilot's got some guts!
A tough opponent!
However...
What amazing power!
What?!
You!
Not bad, Gundam!
But my control systems are still intact!
He's coming!
I knew it!
You're...! That kid from before!
Your name's Amuro?
I get it!
You let us go just so you could
find the White Base.
Unbelievable!
Times certainly have changed,
with kids like you fighting as pilots!
Take this!
Huh? What's he...?!
Impressive! But remember, kid...!
Your own strength didn't win the battle!
It was the performance of your mobile suit!
Don't forget it!
You're just a sore loser!
Wait!
I have no choice.
I'll meet up with Hamon later tonight.
Kai! Ryu!
Fall back!
Top priority is to recover Hayato's Guntank.
We're getting out of here.
We've taken too much damage.
Amuro! Open a comm circuit!
I want you to help with the recovery.
Whatever your reasons were,
you're guilty of damaging our teamwork.
That's too one-sided!
I didn't leave the White Base on a whim!
You have to hear my side of it too!
We can't do that.
Mr. Bright!
When Ramba Ral attacks,
I'll have to pilot the Gundam anyway!
Amuro!
Mr. Ryu!
Why do you think I went looking for you?
Because... without me, you can't fight.
Don't be so conceited.
We just wanted the Gundam back.
You should think long and hard about that!
Eh, Amuro?
Mr. Ryu!
Mr. Kai!
Mr. Ryu!!
We'll have to do repairs all night.
It seems even that Gallop of theirs
got damaged... but they'll be back.
Yeah.
Will he be all right?
You'd understand if you listened to me!
Let me out!
There's no need to lock me up in here!
Mr. Bright! Or even Ms. Mirai!
Ms. Sayla! Please come!
Please hear me out!
Mr. Ryu! Ms. Sayla!
Listen to me... I have things to say too!
Stupid Amuro.
I'm sure you can hear me on the TV monitor.
Answer me! Ms. Sayla! Ms. Sayla!!
I can use...
...the Gundam...
better than anyone!
I'm the best...
I can use it better than anyone!
Don't be so conceited!
Your own strength didn't win the battle!
You won because of Gundam's performance!
You've got guts.
That's why Hamon likes you.
This is my treat, Amuro.
I... I really...
...want to beat that man!
The enemy finally boards the White Base.
The young crew resists the intruders
in the midst of terror.
As guns blaze,
the Gundam destroys the Gallop.
But the cost of this victory is high...
...resulting in significant losses for
Amuro and the crew.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Hand-to-Hand Combat.
Next Time
Hand-to-Hand Combat
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...